Guide to the Sol Yurick Manuscripts for Publication TAM.268
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- "The Library", undated, 1980
  - Electronic Records, 1980; TW_TAM_268_ER_39
- "Picexhib", undated (Box 28)
- "Information, The Future, Technopolitical Economics and Nationalism", undated, 1980 (Box 28)
  - Paper, undated (Box 28)
  - Electronic Records, 1980; TW_TAM_268_ER_19
- "The Situation Room Concept of Malaputa", undated (Box 28)
- "Oediplay", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 28)
- "Why Oedipus?", undated (Box 28)
- "What Really Happened to Oedipus and How it Affected our Lives", undated (Box 28)
- "Outline for a Series of Linked Essays to be Tentatively Called 'Politics in the Imagination'", undated (Box 28)
- "The Future of the Information Age", undated, 1980
  - Paper, undated (Box 28)
  - Electronic Records, 1980; TW_TAM_268_ER_38
- "The Coming of the Technologization of Art", undated (Box 29)
- "Outline for a novel tentatively to be called The Wooden O.", undated (Box 29)
- "The Wooden O. Continued", undated (Box 29)
- "How the Athenians Planned to Trick Freud and Colonize the Mind of the West and Immortalize Themselves aka 'Oediplay'", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 29)
- "On Joseph in Egypt's Model for an Agricultural Revolution", undated (Box 29)
- "On the Deconstruction of the Jews", undated (Box 29)
- "Malaputa", undated; 6 folders 6 folders (Box 29)
- "Gangs, Crews, Posses, Prides and Exaltations", 1990 September 29 - October 1 (Box 29)
- "Invitation to a Bank Burning", 1990-1996
  - Paper, 1990; 3 folders (Box 29)
  - Electronic Records, 1991-1996; TW_TAM_268_ER_20
- "On the Deconstruction of the Jews", 1990-1991; 5 folders 5 folders (Box 29)
- "The Emergence of the Metastate versus Identity Politics", 1990 April (Box 29)
- "How the Athenians Planned to Trick Freud and Colonize the Mind of the West and Immortalize Themselves", undated, 1994-1996, 2000-2002
  - Paper, undated (Box 29)
  - Electronic Records, 1994-1996, 2000-2002; TW_TAM_268_ER_17
- "Within this Wooden O.", 1989; 4 folders 4 folders (Box 29)
- "Oediplay", 1989 September (Box 30)
- "On Sports, Gambling and Steroids", undated (Box 30)
- "Suicide", 1991-1992; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 30)
- "Oedipus: Or The Coup: Or The CIA Oedipus", 1992 January (Box 30)
- "Burning", 1990-1991; 4 folders 3 folders in Box 33 1 folder in Box 34 (Box 30)
- "Euroiden", 1991; 4 folders 4 folders (Box 30)
- "Suicide", 1991; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 30)
- "Invitation to a Bank Burning", 1990; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 30)
- "Poli-Oed", 1989-1990 (Box 30, Box 31)
- "The Deconstruction of the Jews", 1990 May (Box 31)
- Untitled Outline, undated (Box 31)
- "The King of Malaputa", undated; 15 folders (Box 32)
- "Green", undated; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 32)
- "Devlin's Trip into the 'Interior'", undated (Box 32)
- "Later Dreams", undated (Box 32)
- "Destiny Assorted Papers, miscellaneous but important", undated; 4 folders 4 folders (Box 32, Box 33)
- "The King of Malaputa: A Treatment", undated (Box 33)
- "Some Notes Toward a Sociology of Theoretical Obscurity (A Variation on the Thought of Alvin Gouldner)", undated (Box 33)
- "Joseph", 1989 December (Box 33)
- "A Tentative Outline of the Holocaust Museum and Trial Novel-Play", 1990 January 16 (Box 33)
- "Try", 1990 February 19 (Box 33)
- "Oedipus Coup", 1989-2003; 9 folders 9 folders (Box 33)
- "JB" by Ron Dobson, undated (Box 33)
- "Malaputa", undated (Box 33)
- "The Sacrifice" Dobson/Yurick, 1995-1996; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 33)
- "Oedipus Outline, Trial of God, etc.", undated (Box 33)
- "About Joseph", undated (Box 33)
- Opinion letter regarding technology and Marxism, undated (Box 33)
- "This fragment is a double meditation: The first is on finance and the second is on the proposition of Magical Birth", undated (Box 33)
- Fragment on the Relationship Between Capitalism and AIDS, undated (Box 33)
- "Some Theses on Power and Capital as a System of Power", undated (Box 33)
- Untitled Fragment on Jewish Identity, undated (Box 33)
- Untitled Fragment on Marxism and Yurick's Development as an Author, undated (Box 33)
- Untitled Fragment on Evolution, Philosophy, and Capitalism, undated (Box 33)
- Untitled Fragment on Cold War Policy, Literature, and Evolution, undated (Box 33)
- Untitled Fragment Discussing Marxism and Education, undated (Box 33)
- "Political and Cultural Economy of Plague, Population and Proximity", undated (Box 33)
- "On Spreadsheets", 2000-2002
  - Paper, December 2000 (Box 33)
  - Electronic Records, 2000-2002; TW_TAM_268_ER_26
- "Faust", undated (Box 33)
- "Memories in the Context of the End of the Cold War", undated (Box 33)
- "Mater", 1989 May (Box 33)
- Ron Hunnings Interviews with Sol Yurick, 1991 October 19 (Box 34)
- "Capital/ERG", 1989 September 4 (Box 34)
- "A Position Paper of Sorts: The Fate of Social Text in the Context of the Ever-Present Crisis", undated (Box 34)
- "Making: the Realms of Facts vs. the Realm of the Imagination", 1991 February 11 (Box 34)
- "Horizon-Tour/Aronowitz", 1993 November 1 (Box 34)
- Capithese, 1993-1994, 2000
  - Paper, 1993 December; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Electronic Records, 1993-1994, 2000; TW_TAM_268_ER_7
- Miscellaneous Personal Notes, undated; 6 folders 6 folders and 1 USB drive (Box 34)
- "The Sacrifice" Dobson/Yurick, undated
  - Paper, undated; 3 folders (Box 34)
  - Electronic Records, 1994, 2000; TW_TAM_268_ER_43
- "Dionysus at the Beach" Yurick/Dobson/Quigley, 1987 (Box 34)
- "Suite Vengeance" Yurick/Dobson/Quigley, 1987 (Box 34)
- "Body Parts" Dobson/Yurick, undated (Box 34)
- "Gigaflop" Yurick/Krass, undated (Box 34)
- Various Notes, undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 34)
- "The Harvesting", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 34)
- "How the Athenians Planned to Trick Freud and Colonize the Mind of the West and Immortalize Themselves", 1989 August; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 34)
- "Oedipus", 1989 August 6 (Box 34)
- "Oediplay", 1989 August 5 (Box 34)
- "On Jews", undated (Box 34)
- "On the Deconstruction of the Jews", 1990; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 34)
- "Welcome to the Holocaust Memnotechuem" or "Try", 1990; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 35)
- "Some notes toward a sociology of theoretical obscurity (A variation on the thought of Alvin Gouldner)", undated (Box 35)
- "On Joseph in Egypt's Model for an Agricultural Revolution", undated (Box 35)
- "Malaputa (Auction)", 1989 March; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 35)
- "The Auction", 1989 March; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 35)
- "Oedipus, or The Coup", 1989 February (Box 35)
- "Project for a Novel: Within this Wooden O", 1989 January - March (Box 35)
- "Within this Wooden O", 1989; 9 folders 9 folders (Box 35)
- "Oediplay", undated (Box 35)
- "The Mystery of the Inner World", undated (Box 35)
- "Semiotext(e)" (includes "The Great Escape" by Sol Yurick), undated (Box 35)
- Fertig (photocopy of book jacket and Chapters 1-20), 1966; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 35)
- "Within this Wooden O", 1989 December 8 (Box 35)
- Outline for "Within this Wooden O", 1989 December 9 (Box 35)
- "Ellsburg as Ishmael: Rostow as Ahab", 1971 (Box 35)
- "Ellsburg as Ishmael: Nixon as Ahab", undated (Box 35)
- "Selby: Symbolic Intent and Ideological Resistance or Cocksucking and Revolution", undated (Box 35)
- "The Harvesting", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 35)
- "Once Upon a Time", undated (Box 35)
- "The Political Economy of a Junkie's Death", undated (Box 35)
- "On Making Foreign Policy with your Feet" and "The Black Badge", undated (Box 35)
- "A Short Note on the Burden of Proof" and "Symposium Questionnaire", undated (Box 35)
- "This Age of Gold", undated (Box 35)
- "And a Friend to Sit by Your Side", undated (Box 35)
- "Jackie Marries Onassis: An Epithalamium" (Box 35)
- Reviews, 1966-1970; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 35)
- "Burning the Bank of America", undated; 4 folders 4 folders (Box 36)
- Contracts Borchardt, 1968-1985; 5 folders 5 folders (Box 36)
- "Within this Wooden O", 1992 November (Box 36)
- "Oedipus, or The Coup, or the CIA Oedipus", 1992 November - December (Box 36)
- "How the Athenians Planned to Trick Freud and Colonize the Mind of the West and Immortalize Themselves", undated (Box 36)
- "The King of Malaputa", 1991 February - April (Box 36)
- "Project for a Novel: Within this Wooden O", undated (Box 36)
- Draft of a letter addressed to Stanley and Bill, undated (Box 36)
- "Burning of the Bank of America" (fragment), 1993 January (Box 36)
- "The Emergence of the Metastate, the Politics of Ethno-Nationalist Identity, and the Global Multicultural War of All Against All", 1993-1994; 5 folders 5 folders (Box 36, Box 37)
- "An Act of Imagination. Finding out that the Jews Were Not the Only Ones Who Had Undergone Genocide, Remembering the Armenian Genocide", undated (Box 37)
- "The Arena", undated (Box 37)
- "Joseph", undated (Box 37)
- "Oedipus" and "Wooden O" (fragment), 1989 February (Box 37)
- "Climbing a Crystal Staircase: Moses Sheldon Hall", undated (Box 37)
- "The Destiny Algorithm", 1994 January 16 (Box 37)
- "Some Theses on Power and Capital as a System of Power", undated (Box 37)
- "Euroiden/Commu-end version", 1993 December 17 (Box 37)
- "Within this Wooden O" (fragment), 1994 February 1 (Box 37)
- "Fausts stages of Spiritual/Economic Growth and Takeoff Into Transcendence" (fragments), undated (Box 37)
- Handwritten Notes, circa 1985 (Box 37)
- "Oedipus, or the Coup", 1989-1996, 2000-2002, 2007-2008
  - Paper, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Electronic Records, 1989-1996, 2000-2002, 2007-2008; TW_TAM_268_ER_25
- "Faust", undated (Box 37)
- Handwritten Notes and Outlines, 1990, 1992, 1994, 2000, 2010-2011
  - Paper, undated (Box 37)
  - Electronic Records, 1990, 1992, 1994, 2000, 2010-2011; TW_TAM_268_ER_16
- "How the Athenians Plotted to Infiltrate and Colonize the Mind of the West and Immortalize Themselves", 1994 March (Box 37)
- "Proposal for a Production to be Called Arena" By Yurick, Ronald, Dobson, Chip, and Quigley, undated (Box 37)
- "On the Deconstruction of the Jews", undated (Box 37)
- "Suite Vengeance: A Treatment" By Yurick, Dobson, and Quigley, undated (Box 37)
- "Burning", 1991-1992; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 37)
- "And, As We Once Again Begin Our Story Outline Here We Should Have an Overall Statement of the Novel", undated (Box 37)
- "Suicide", 1992 February - March (Box 37)
- "On the Deconstruction of the Jews", 1995; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 37)
- Handwritten Notes, undated (Box 37)
- "The Sacrifice" By Sol Yurick and Ron Dobson, undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 37)
- "Burning", 1994; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 37)
- "Oediplay" (fragment), undated (Box 37)
- "Behold the Metatron, the Recording Angel", undated (Box 37)
- "Outline of Climbing a Crystal Staircase: The Moses Hall Story", undated (Box 37)
- "Poly-Oed" (fragment), undated (Box 37)
- "Jew decon", 1992-1995 (Box 37)
- "The Emergence of the EuroAmerican Dominated Metastate versus the Politics of Identity", undated (Box 37)
- "Moses Hall", undated (Box 37)
- "Within this Wooden O", 1989, 1993 (Box 37)
- Fragments of Typescript drafts, undated (Box 37)
- "Bank Burning", 1993-1994 (Box 37)
- "Samel's Sermon: A Tour of the Horizon", 1994 September (Box 38)
- "Oedipus, or The Coup", 1993-1994; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 38)
- "Euro-iden", 1980 January 1 (Box 38)
- "Burning the Bank of America", 1992 (Box 38)
- "Suicide", 1992; 4 folders 4 folders (Box 38)
- "The Destiny Algorithm", 1992; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 39)
- "Bereshit: Or the Great Escape", 1992 October - November (Box 39)
- "Deconstruction of the Jews", 1992 October (Box 39)
- Drew University: Interface with Sol Yurick (VHS recording), 1989 January; 1 videocassette (Box 40)
- "Moses Hall" (audio recording), undated; 6 audiocassettes (Box 40)
- Kapital by Karl Marx - Annotated Copy, undated (Box 41)
- In Cold Blood by Truman Capote - Annotated Copy, undated (Box 41)
- Structural Anthropology by Claude Lvi-Strauss - Annotated Copy, undated (Box 41)
- Intervention: Confronting the Real Life Risks of Genetic Engineering and Life on a Biotech Planet by Denise Caruso - Annotated Copy, 2006 (Box 41)
- Literary Journals Featuring Stories by Sol Yurick, 1960-1980 (Box 41)
- Bachelor of Arts Diploma New York University, 1951 (Box Shared Tamiment MSOS006, Folder 1)
- "An Essay on the Events of September 11, 2001 Addressed to the Anti-globalization Movement", TW_TAM_268_ER_1
- "Some Thoughts on the Relationship Between Architecture, Aesthetics, Capital, Catastrophe (Natural and Human-Made) and Human Needs", 2000; TW_TAM_268_ER_3
- Correspondence: Richard Cummings, 1995; TW_TAM_268_ER_11
- "Four Preconditions For An Ascent To Heaven", 1997, 2000; TW_TAM_268_ER_15
- "Meditation on Debt-Redemption Accountancy or: An Instance of Class Warfare on the Plains", 2007, 2011-2012; TW_TAM_268_ER_23
- "Pictures at a Postmodern, Para-Monumental Exhibition", 1980; TW_TAM_268_ER_28
- "Proposal for an Essay, to be Called: Oedipus, Nixon and Dynasty", 1980; TW_TAM_268_ER_29
- "Revenge", 2007-2011; TW_TAM_268_ER_31
- Short Articles & Essays, 1980, 1988-1991, 1993-2012; TW_TAM_268_ER_32
- "Short Visions of Things to Come in the New Communication's Order", 1990-1991; TW_TAM_268_ER_34
- "Spiking the Cannon", 2011; TW_TAM_268_ER_36
- "The Oedipus Complex and Cloning Complex", 2001; TW_TAM_268_ER_40
- "Various Novels and Pieces Strung Together and Yet Interlocking", 2001; TW_TAM_268_ER_44
- "Preconditions for an Ascent to Heaven", 1997, 2000; TW_TAM_268_ER_46
- "A Meditation on the Culture War...", 2011; TW_TAM_268_ER_47